I must say, sir.
‫لا أخفيك سرًا يا سيدي.‬
You have found an excellent property for yourself.
‫لقد وجدت عقارًا ممتازًا لنفسك.‬
This place is only 20 minutes by car from the center of Berlin.
‫هذا المكان يبعد 20 دقيقة فقط بالسيارة‬ ‫عن وسط "برلين".‬
BERLIN (FORMER EAST GERMAN SIDE)
‫"(برلين)، جانب (ألمانيا الشرقية) سابقًا"‬
You'll never find another estate as nice as this in former East Germany.
‫لن تجد ضيعة أخرى بهذا الجمال‬ ‫في "ألمانيا الشرقية" سابقًا.‬
I believe this used to be the house of Mr. Liebert,
‫أعتقد أن هذا كان منزل السيد "ليبرت"،‬
an adviser in the former East German Trade Bureau.
‫الذي كان مستشارًا‬ ‫لمكتب التجارة في "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬
Huh?
‫ماذا؟‬
What? You're only here to inquire about Mr. Liebert?
‫ماذا؟ هل جئت فقط لتستعلم عن السيد "ليبرت"؟‬
You're not a client?
‫ألست عميلًا؟‬
I'm sorry, but there is something I need to know.
‫آسف، لكن يوجد شيء يجب أن أعرفه.‬
I don't know about a government official who defected ten years ago.
‫لا أعرف شيئًا عن مسؤول حكومي‬ ‫انشقّ قبل عشرة أعوام.‬
When Mr. and Mrs. Liebert were here,
‫حين كان السيد والسيدة "ليبرت" هنا،‬
I believe they adopted a pair of twins.
‫أظن أنهما قاما بتبنّي توأمين.‬
I told you I don't know.
‫أخبرتك بأنني لا أعرف.‬
Who is the landowner of this place? Can you introduce us?
‫من هو مالك هذا المكان؟‬ ‫أيمكنك أن تعرّفني به؟‬
Most of the old East German properties belong
‫معظم العقارات القديمة في "ألمانيا الشرقية"‬
to wealthy Jews who fled during the Nazi regime.
‫كانت ملكًا لليهود الأثرياء‬ ‫الذين هربوا في أثناء الحكم النازي.‬
The Eastern government is paying foreign countries
‫الحكومة الشرقية تدفع للدول الأجنبية‬
as well as the West to rent the land.
‫وكذلك للجانب الغربي مقابل استئجار الأرض.‬
The owner of this place lives overseas too.
‫مالك هذا المكان يعيش خارج البلاد أيضًا.‬
Also, our real estate company is from the West,
‫كما أن شركتنا العقارية من الجانب الغربي،‬
and we only expanded after the Wall fell.
‫ولم نتوسّع إلا بعد سقوط الجدار.‬
So we don't know anything about the old stories.
‫لذا لا نعرف شيئًا عن القصص القديمة.‬
Come on. I'm locking up, so please leave.
‫هيا. سأوصد البوابة، فانصرف من فضلك.‬
Does anyone know what happened ten years ago?
‫هل يعرف أحد ماذا حدث قبل عشرة أعوام؟‬
Would anyone remember Mr. Liebert?
‫هل يمكنني إيجاد من يتذكّر السيد "ليبرت"؟‬
Like I said earlier, this was
‫كما قلت سابقًا،‬
the residential district of the former top government officials.
‫كان هذا الحي السكني‬ ‫يضمّ كبار المسؤولين الحكوميين السابقين.‬
Most of them scattered once the Wall fell.
‫تفرّق معظمهم بمجرد سقوط الجدار.‬
Especially those in the Ministry of the Interior.
‫خاصةً من كانوا مسؤولين في وزارة الداخلية.‬
Oh, now I think of it…
‫الآن وقد ذكّرتني…‬
A former East German Trade Bureau official is ten houses down.
‫هناك مسؤول أسبق من مكتب تجارة‬ ‫"ألمانيا الشرقية" على بُعد عشرة منازل.‬
Ah, Mr. Liebert?
‫السيد "ليبرت"؟‬
He didn't have to risk everything to defect,
‫لم يكن من الضروري أن يجازف بكل شيء لينشقّ،‬
since he could have patiently waited for East Germany to fall.
‫إذ كان بوسعه أن ينتظر بصبر‬ ‫حتى تسقط "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬
I don't get why he went to the free country, anyway.
‫لا أفهم سبب ذهابه إلى البلد الحرّ‬ ‫على أي حال.‬
He was even murdered.
‫لقد قُتل.‬
Did Mr. Liebert have a pair of twins?
‫هل كان السيد "ليبرت" يرعى توأمين؟‬
Twins? Hmm…
‫توأمان؟‬
Ah, I remember!
‫تذكّرت!‬
The twins Mr. Liebert adopted from the orphanage!
‫التوأمان اللذان تبنّاهما السيد "ليبرت"‬ ‫من الميتم!‬
The orphanage?
‫الميتم؟‬
They were cute kids.
‫كانا طفلين ظريفين.‬
Mr. Liebert always wanted kids of his own.
‫لطالما أراد السيد "ليبرت" أطفالًا.‬
Wh… Where is that orphanage?
‫أين ذلك الميتم؟‬
Hmm. Let's see…
‫دعني أتذكّر…‬
Oh, right! I think it's Kinderheim 511.
‫أجل! أظن أنه"كيندرهايم 511".‬
This place used to be an orphanage,
‫كان هذا المكان ملجأً للأيتام،‬
but soon it will be a supermarket.
‫لكنه سيتحوّل قريبًا إلى سوق غذائي.‬
I'm glad that this disturbing building will finally be torn down.
‫أنا سعيدة‬ ‫لأن هذه البناية الكئيبة ستُهدم أخيرًا.‬
Excuse me. Do you know where I can find the employees who worked in the orphanage?
‫معذرةً. أتعرفين أين يمكنني أن أجد الموظّفين‬ ‫الذين عملوا في الميتم؟‬
Employees? There's no one left, of course.
‫موظّفون؟ لم يبق أحد بالطبع.‬
I don't want to talk about this place since it gives me the chills.
‫لا أريد التحدّث عن هذا المكان‬ ‫لأنه يصيبني بالقشعريرة.‬
Ex… Excuse me!
‫معذرةً!‬
If you really want to know,
‫إن كنت مصرًا على أن تعرف،‬
a man named Hartmann who used to work in the Ministry of Health is in No. 47.
‫فهناك رجل يُدعى "هارتمان"‬ ‫كان يعمل في وزارة الصحة، في البناية 47.‬
Hey, boy.
‫مرحبًا يا فتى.‬
Does a man named Hartmann live around here?
‫هل يعيش هنا رجل يُدعى "هارتمان"؟‬
What's wrong? You're hurt!
‫ما الخطب؟ أنت مصاب.‬
Let me see.
‫دعني أرى.‬
It's okay. Don't be scared. Just let me see.
‫لا بأس. لا تخف. دعني أرى فحسب.‬
Your injury is still healing
‫لم يُشف جرحك بعد‬
and now it's festering since it's injured again.
‫والآن تقيّح لأن المكان نفسه جُرح مرة أخرى.‬
Just bear with it. It will sting a bit, but you'll get better.
‫تحمّل قليلًا. سيوخزك بعض الشيء، لكنك ستتحسّن.‬
Okay, good.
‫حسنًا، جيد.‬
Don't fall!
‫لا تسقط!‬
Or you'll get hurt again.
‫وإلا أُصبت مجددًا.‬
"Hartmann."
‫"هارتمان".‬
After the Wall came down, I took in all those children
‫بعد سقوط الجدار، آويت كل هؤلاء الأطفال‬
and became their foster parent.
‫ووفّرت لهم الرعاية البديلة.‬
Foster parent?
‫الرعاية البديلة؟‬
Yes. I raised them until they were adopted
‫أجل. ربّيتهم حتى يتمّ تبنّيهم‬
or until they could live on their own.
‫أو حتى يصبحوا قادرين على العيش بمفردهم.‬
The child in the middle was adopted by the president of an apparel company.
‫الطفل الذي ترى صورته في المنتصف‬ ‫تبنّاه رئيس شركة ملابس.‬
The one on the left is now serving in the military.
‫الطفل على اليسار يخدم الآن في الجيش.‬
In fact, I'm taking care of one right now.
‫في الواقع، أنا أرعى صبيًا حاليًا.‬
It must be hard work.
‫لا بد أنه عمل شاق.‬
I don't know if I would call it work.
‫لا أعرف إن كنت أسمّيه عملًا.‬
In the Ministry of Health, I spent a long time working with orphanages.
‫في وزارة الصحة، قضيت وقتًا طويلًا‬ ‫في العمل مع دور الأيتام.‬
Since then, I have always been against the government.
‫منذ ذلك الحين، كنت دائمًا معارضًا للحكومة.‬
After socialism collapsed,
‫بعد انهيار الاشتراكية،‬
I thought I could help the children in my own way.
‫رأيت أنني أستطيع مساعدة الأطفال‬ ‫بطريقتي الخاصة.‬
Since I am poor, it is not going as well as I had planned.
‫بما أنني فقير، فالأمر لا يسير كما خططت له.‬
However, they are still much better off than when they were in the orphanage.
‫ومع ذلك فإنهم في حال أفضل بكثير‬ ‫مما كانوا في الميتم.‬
Kinderheim 511 was
‫كان ميتم "كيندرهايم 511"‬
a special orphanage run by the Ministries of Health and the Interior.
‫دار أيتام خاصّة‬ ‫تديرها وزارتا الصحة والداخلية.‬
Well, that's what East German orphanages were like.
‫هكذا كانت دور الأيتام‬ ‫في "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬
For the most part, anyway.
‫معظمها على الأقل.‬
But even then, the special orphanages were the very worst.
‫لكن حتى في ذلك الحين، كانت دور الأيتام‬ ‫الخاصّة هي الأسوأ على الإطلاق.‬
It wasn't just a facility for children who had no place to go.
‫لم تكن مجرد منشأة للأطفال‬ ‫المحرومين من المأوى.‬
They were children of criminals and political prisoners who tried to flee.
‫بل كانوا أبناء المجرمين والسجناء السياسيين‬ ‫الذين حاولوا الفرار.‬
Their parents were people accused of crimes like rebellion or espionage.
‫كان آباؤهم أشخاصًا متهمين بجرائم‬ ‫مثل التمرّد أو التجسّس.‬
That's why they were subjected to discrimination and inhumane treatment.
‫لهذا السبب كانوا يتعرّضون إلى التمييز‬ ‫والمعاملة غير الإنسانية.‬
The children couldn't fight back, no matter what was inflicted.
‫لم يستطع الأطفال المقاومة‬ ‫مهما أُنزل بهم من تعذيب.‬
That place embodied the contradiction between socialism and totalitarianism.
‫كان ذلك المكان يجسّد التناقض‬ ‫بين الاشتراكية والشمولية.‬
In their propaganda, the government said
‫في الدعاية الحكومية، كانوا يقولون‬
that they would re-educate the children to become the models of socialism.
‫إنهم سيعيدون تثقيف الأطفال‬ ‫ليصبحوا نماذج للاشتراكية.‬
In reality, they treated them like criminals.
‫لكنهم على أرض الواقع،‬ ‫كانوا يعاملونهم كمجرمين.‬
On top of that, the director and educators were horrible.
‫علاوةً على ذلك،‬ ‫كان مدير الميتم والمعلّمون وحشيين.‬
The worst ones would
‫وكان أسوأهم‬
even confiscate and sell the packages sent to the children.
‫يصادرون ويبيعون طرود الإعانات‬ ‫المرسلة إلى الأطفال.‬
It makes you wonder who the real criminals were.
‫هذا يجعلك تتساءل،‬ ‫من هم المجرمون الحقيقيون؟‬
Fear and violence controlled the special orphanages.
‫كان الخوف والعنف‬ ‫يهيمنان على دور الأيتام الخاصّة.‬
It was impossible to raise a normal person.
‫كان من المستحيل أن تنشئ إنسانًا طبيعيًا.‬
Then, that incident happened.
‫ثم وقعت تلك الحادثة.‬
The incident? What happened at the orphanage?
‫الحادثة؟ ماذا حدث في الميتم؟‬
You said that you wanted
‫قلت إنك تريد‬
to ask about those twins, right?
‫أن تسأل عن التوأمين، صحيح؟‬
Do you know something about them?
‫هل تعرف شيئًا عنهما؟‬
The sister was placed in an orphanage
‫وُضعت الأخت في ميتم‬
in another district, so I don't know much about her.
‫في مقاطعة أخرى، لذا لا أعرف الكثير عنها.‬
However, I know a lot about her brother, Johan.
‫لكنني أعرف الكثير عن أخيها "يوهان".‬
Johan… That's right. I want to ask you about Johan!
‫"يوهان". هذا صحيح.‬ ‫أريد أن أسألك عن "يوهان"!‬
That… That was top secret.
‫كان هذا سرّي للغاية.‬
The government of East Germany issued a gag order about it.
‫أصدرت حكومة "ألمانيا الشرقية"‬ ‫أمرًا رسميًا بتكتّم الأمر.‬
Well, it's all in the past now.
‫لكن، كل هذا صار من الماضي.‬
It would be okay to talk about the incident, but…
‫لا بأس بالتحدّث عن الحادثة، لكن…‬
What happened?
‫ماذا حدث؟‬
He led a revolution.
‫تزعّم ثورة.‬
I'm home.
‫لقد عدت إلى المنزل.‬
Dieter. Say hi to our guest.
‫"ديتر". ألق التحية على ضيفنا.‬
What's that attitude? Where are your manners?
‫ما هذا السلوك؟ أين آدابك؟‬
It's fine. We met in front of the house earlier.
‫لا بأس. التقينا أمام المنزل قبل قليل.‬
Right?
‫صحيح؟‬
Anyway, about what we were talking about just now…
‫على أي حال، بشأن ما كنا نتحدّث للتوّ…‬
Sorry, I don't want to discuss that in front of the child.
‫آسف، لا أريد مناقشة ذلك أمام الطفل.‬
Yes, you are right.
‫أجل، أنت على حق.‬
It's getting late, so I will stop by again some other time.
‫لقد تأخر الوقت، لذا سأزورك في وقت آخر.‬
Would you like to have dinner with us?
‫أتودّ تناول العشاء معنا؟‬
Mr. Tenma. Since you're a freelance journalist,
‫سيد "تينما". بما أنك صحافي مستقلّ،‬
you will write an article about the things you're researching, right?
‫فإنك ستكتب مقالًا‬ ‫عن الأمور التي تبحث عنها، صحيح؟‬
Ye… Yeah.
‫أجل.‬
Then please make sure
‫إذًا احرص من فضلك‬
you write down this point.
‫على كتابة هذه النقطة.‬
The growth of a child depends entirely on the adult raising him.
‫نمو الطفل يعتمد كليًا‬ ‫على الراشد الذي يربّيه.‬
We must lead our children down the right path.
‫يجب أن نرشد أولادنا إلى الطريق الصحيح.‬
It's only then the children can realize their wonderful dreams for the first time.
‫هذا هو السبيل الوحيد إلى تحقيق الأطفال‬ ‫لأحلامهم الرائعة لأول مرة.‬
Dreams…
‫أحلام…‬
Dieter, what's your dream?
‫"ديتر"، ما هو حلمك؟‬
Soccer ball…
‫كرة القدم…‬
I want to have a soccer ball.
‫أريد أن أمتلك كرة قدم.‬
I see.
‫فهمت.‬
Thank you for dinner. I hope to continue our conversation next time.
‫أشكرك على العشاء.‬ ‫أرجو أن نكمل حديثنا في المرة القادمة.‬
I'm sorry our conversation was interrupted.
‫أعتذر عن مقاطعة حديثنا.‬
I will come back again. I'll contact you tomorrow.
‫سأعود مرة أخرى. سأتصل بك غدًا.‬
Dieter.
‫"ديتر".‬
Excuse me!
‫معذرةً!‬
Can I come in?
‫أيمكنني الدخول؟‬
Mr. Hartmann! It's me, Tenma.
‫سيد "هارتمان"! هذا أنا، "تينما".‬
Mr. Hartmann!
‫سيد "هارتمان"!‬
What happened? Mr. Hartmann!
‫ماذا حدث؟ سيد "هارتمان"!‬
Mr. Hartmann…
‫سيد "هارتمان"…‬
Mr. Tenma.
‫سيد "تينما".‬
Dieter!
‫"ديتر"!‬
-What happened? -He fell.
‫- ماذا جرى؟‬ ‫- لقد سقط.‬
He got on the chair and… Ah! Dieter.
‫وقف على الكرسي ثم…‬
It hurts! It hurts so much!
‫هذا مؤلم! الألم شديد!‬
Where does it hurt, Dieter?
‫أين موضع الألم يا "ديتر"؟‬
It hurts!
‫هذا مؤلم!‬
Mr. Hartmann, call an ambulance!
‫سيد "هارتمان"، استدع سيارة إسعاف!‬
Dieter, let me see.
‫"ديتر"، دعني أرى.‬
What's this? Why do you have all these injuries?
‫ما هذا؟ ما سبب كل هذه الإصابات؟‬
Is it here?
‫هل الألم هنا؟‬
Does this hurt?
‫أهذا مؤلم؟‬
Two ribs are broken.
‫ضلعان مكسوران.‬
The left shoulder is dislocated.
‫الكتف الأيسر مخلوع.‬
How can he be this hurt just from falling off the chair?
‫كيف تلحق به كل هذه الإصابات‬ ‫جرّاء السقوط عن كرسي فحسب؟‬
The ambulance should be here soon.
‫ستصل سيارة الإسعاف بعد قليل.‬
So, we should be fine.
‫إذًا سنكون بخير.‬
Ah… Okay.
‫حسنًا.‬
But what are these injuries from?
‫لكن ما سبب هذه الإصابات؟‬
I told you it will be okay.
‫أخبرتك بأن الأمور ستكون بخير.‬
So, it's time for you to leave.
‫لذا، حان الوقت لتنصرف.‬
But…
‫لكن…‬
More importantly, the way you touched his wounds…
‫الأهم من ذلك، أن أسلوبك في لمس جروحه…‬
It's like you're a doctor.
‫يدلّ على أنك طبيب.‬
Uh… No…
‫لا…‬
Tenma… I thought that name sounded familiar.
‫"تينما"…‬
You're a doctor, right?
‫أنت طبيب، صحيح؟‬
You're the doctor wanted for murder.
‫أنت الطبيب المطلوب بتهمة القتل.‬
All these injuries… Where did he get all these injuries?
‫كل هذه الإصابات…‬
More importantly, Mr. Tenma…
‫الأهم من ذلك يا سيد "تينما"…‬
I think it's best for you to start running.
‫أظن أنه من الأفضل لك أن تبدأ الهروب.‬
When I called the ambulance, I also called the police.
‫حين طلبت سيارة الإسعاف،‬ ‫اتصلت بالشرطة أيضًا.‬
Mr. Hartmann! I'm asking you.
‫سيد "هارتمان"! إنني أسألك.‬
How did Dieter get these injuries?
‫كيف لحقت بـ"ديتر" هذه الإصابات؟‬
You're a fugitive who is being chased for murder.
‫أنت فارّ من العدالة، ملاحق بتهمة القتل.‬
I suppose a fugitive would have a short temper.
‫لا عجب في أن يكون الفارّ من العدالة‬ ‫حادّ المزاج.‬
Did you do this to him?
‫هل فعلت هذا به؟‬
Did what?
‫ماذا فعلت؟‬
You have been abusing Dieter.
‫أنت تنتهك إنسانية "ديتر".‬
Abuse?
‫أنتهك إنسانيته؟‬
I wish you wouldn't say such a terrible thing.
‫ليتك لا تقول هذا الكلام المسيئ.‬
Don't you agree, Dieter?
‫ألا توافقني الرأي يا "ديتر"؟‬
What are you going to do?
‫ماذا ستفعل؟‬
I'm taking him to the hospital.
‫سآخذه إلى المستشفى.‬
After the murders, now it's kidnapping for you?
‫بعد جرائم القتل،‬ ‫هل ستضيف جريمة اختطاف أيضًا؟‬
Don't move!
‫لا تتحرّك!‬
Even if you do that, you'll get caught right away.
‫حتى إن فعلت ذلك، فستُعتقل على الفور.‬
Don't worry, Dieter. I'll take you to the hospital now.
‫لا تقلق يا "ديتر".‬ ‫سآخذك إلى المستشفى الآن.‬
I'm scared of the hospital.
‫أنا خائف من المستشفى.‬
Don't be scared.
‫لا تخف.‬
The doctor will take good care of you.
‫سيحسن الطبيب رعايتك.‬
Mr. Hartmann would… always treat my injuries for me.
‫السيد "هارتمان" يعالج إصاباتي دائمًا.‬
You have all these injuries, but you've never been to a hospital?
‫ألديك كل هذه الإصابات،‬ ‫ولم تذهب إلى مستشفى قط؟‬
I'm scared… So many scary things in this world.
‫أنا خائف…‬
That's why I have to be strong.
‫لهذا يجب أن أكون قويًا.‬
Strong…
‫قويًا…‬
Did Mr. Hartmann tell you that?
‫هل قال لك السيد "هارتمان" هذا الكلام؟‬
The world is a horrible place, and tomorrow is dark.
‫العالم مكان فظيع، والغد مظلم.‬
That's not true.
‫هذا ليس صحيحًا.‬
The world being a horrible place is a complete lie!
‫قوله إن العالم مكان فظيع كذب!‬
Really?
‫حقًا؟‬
Yes, really.
‫أجل، حقًا.‬
Ah, I almost forgot.
‫كدت أن أنسى.‬
Here, a soccer ball.
‫تفضّل، كرة قدم.‬
Tomorrow will be a good day.
‫غدًا سيكون يومًا سعيدًا.‬
I'm sorry for troubling you so late at night.
‫أعتذر عن إزعاجك في هذا الوقت المتأخر‬ ‫من الليل.‬
It's fine, but we're busy with patients in emergency now.
‫لا بأس، لكننا مشغولون بالمرضى‬ ‫في قسم الطوارئ الآن.‬
It will take some time until the doctor can see him.
‫سيستغرق الأمر بعض الوقت‬ ‫حتى يتمكّن طبيب من فحصه.‬
I know, but please help him…
‫أعرف، لكنني أرجوك أن تساعديه…‬
-There was a big car accident. -The bus driver died on the spot.
‫- وقع حادث مروري كبير.‬ ‫- مات سائق الحافلة في موقع الحادث.‬
We need to ask the truck driver
‫يجب أن نسأل سائق الشاحنة‬
about the accident.
‫عن الحادث.‬
He can still talk with two broken legs, right?
‫لا يزال بوسعه أن يتكلّم‬ ‫وإن كانت ساقاه مكسورتين، أليس كذلك؟‬
We need to prioritize his treatment. Please question him later.
‫يجب أن نعطي الأولوية لعلاجه.‬ ‫أرجو استجوابه في وقت آخر.‬
Fine, in that case,
‫حسنًا، في هذه الحالة،‬
we'll wait here.
‫سننتظر هنا.‬
Uh, sorry. I'll be back in two hours.
‫آسف. سأعود بعد ساعتين.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Please take good care of that boy.
‫أرجوك أن تحسني رعاية ذلك الصبي.‬
Also, if anybody comes to pick up the boy,
‫وأيضًا، إن جاء أحد لأخذ الصبي،‬
please do not let him go with them.
‫أرجوك ألّا تسمحي لهم بأخذه.‬
Please.
‫أرجوك.‬
Uh… Excuse me!
‫معذرةً!‬
Is the accident scene cleaned up?
‫هل أُزيلت آثار الحادث من الموقع؟‬
No, the traffic is still bad.
‫كلا، لا يزال المرور مزدحمًا.‬
Now, what should I do?
‫والآن، ماذا أفعل؟‬
First, I have to find a place for Dieter to stay.
‫أولًا، يجب أن أجد مكانًا يقيم فيه "ديتر".‬
Even if I take him to the police, I can't go with him.
‫حتى إن أخذته إلى الشرطة،‬ ‫فلا يمكنني الذهاب معه.‬
The sister was placed
‫وُضعت الأخت‬
in an orphanage in another district, so I don't know much about her.
‫في ميتم في مقاطعة أخرى،‬ ‫لذا لا أعرف الكثير عنها.‬
Another orphanage?
‫ميتم آخر؟‬
That's it!
‫وجدتها!‬
Did you say you have a child for us to take in?
‫هل قلت إن لديك طفلًا تريدنا أن نؤويه؟‬
Who exactly are you?
‫من أنت بالضبط؟‬
You came to us so late at night.
‫أتيت إلينا في وقت متأخر جدًا من الليل.‬
I know I'm asking a lot of you.
‫أعرف أنني أطلب منك الكثير.‬
But that boy…
‫لكن ذلك الصبي…‬
I know you said that the boy was being abused.
‫أعرف أنك قلت إن الصبي‬ ‫قد تعرّض إلى عنف شديد.‬
But I have to know who you are.
‫لكنني يجب أن أعرف من أنت.‬
Uh… Well…
‫في الواقع…‬
How can you expect me
‫كيف تتوقع مني‬
to simply take a child from someone I know nothing about?
‫أن آخذ طفلًا من شخص لا أعرف عنه شيئًا؟‬
Um… Can you tell me if this is
‫هل يمكنك أن تخبريني إن كان هذا‬
the orphanage where Anna Liebert was in?
‫هو الميتم الذي أقامت فيه "آنا ليبرت"؟‬
Anna Liebert?
‫"آنا ليبرت"؟‬
Do you know Anna Liebert?
‫هل تعرف "آنا ليبرت"؟‬
So, Anna was here?
‫إذًا، هل كانت "آنا" هنا؟‬
It's been a while.
‫مضى وقت طويل.‬
Where is Anna? How is she?
‫أين "آنا"؟ كيف حالها؟‬
Uh… Well.
‫إنها بخير.‬
Really? So she's doing well, I see.
‫حقًا؟ إذًا أحوالها على ما يُرام.‬
Anna was a good girl.
‫كانت "آنا" فتاة صالحة.‬
The last thing I knew was that she was adopted by
‫آخر شيء عرفته هو أنه قد تبنّاها‬
Mr. Liebert, the Trade Bureau adviser, with her twin brother.
‫السيد "ليبرت" مستشار مكتب التجارة،‬ ‫مع أخيها التوأم.‬
Uh… What's his name?
‫ما اسمه؟‬
It's Johan.
‫اسمه "يوهان".‬
Yes, Johan.
‫أجل، "يوهان".‬
They were really close.
‫كانا مقرّبين جدًا.‬
It was so sad that they were placed in different orphanages.
‫كان من المحزن جدًا‬ ‫أنهما وُضعا في ميتمين مختلفين.‬
Before they came to this orphanage, they only had each other.
‫قبل أن يأتيا إلى هذه الدار،‬ ‫لم يكن لأحدهما سوى الآخر.‬
When they were taken in at the border with Czechoslovakia,
‫حين أُخذا على حدودنا مع "تشيكوسلوفاكيا"،‬
they were trembling with cold and walking hand in hand.
‫كانا يرتجفان من البرد‬ ‫ويسيران متشابكي اليدين.‬
When Mr. Liebert wanted to adopt,
‫حين قرّر السيد "ليبرت" التبنّي،‬
he originally only wanted to adopt Johan.
‫أراد في البداية أن يتبنّى "يوهان" فقط.‬
But Johan said he wouldn't go without his sister.
‫لكن قال "يوهان" إنه لن يذهب من دون أخته.‬
I suppose that made things better for Anna.
‫أظن أن هذا قد حسّن ظروف "آنا".‬
I heard that the orphanages in the East were terrible.
‫سمعت بأن دور الأيتام في الجانب الشرقي‬ ‫كانت فظيعة.‬
Please don't think that we are like Kinderheim 511.
‫أرجوك ألّا تتصوّر‬ ‫أننا مثل ميتم "كيندرهايم 511".‬
Inge. That's not the way to the bathroom.
‫"إنغي". هذا ليس الطريق إلى الحمّام.‬
Come on now.
‫تعالي.‬
Mommy!
‫أمي!‬
It's okay. Don't be scared.
‫لا بأس. لا تخافي.‬
You can go to the bathroom by yourself, right?
‫يمكنك الذهاب إلى الحمّام بمفردك، صحيح؟‬
Those children don't know what a parent's love is like.
‫هؤلاء الأطفال لا يعرفون حب الوالدين.‬
People need love in order to grow.
‫يحتاج الناس إلى الحب حتى يكبروا.‬
Just like you said, the orphanages in the East
‫كما قلت، دور الأيتام في الجانب الشرقي‬
were absolutely horrible.
‫كانت رهيبة.‬
This place used to be called Orphanage No. 47,
‫كان هذا المكان يُسمّى الميتم رقم 47،‬
but we did our best to make it a nice place for the kids.
‫لكننا بذلنا قصارى جهدنا‬ ‫حتى نجعله مكانًا لطيفًا للأطفال.‬
We didn't want to be controlled by the government.
‫لم نرد أن تسيطر علينا الحكومة.‬
At least, not like Kinderheim 511.
‫على الأقل، ليس مثل "كيندرهايم 511".‬
They were under the joint control of the Ministries of Health and the Interior.
‫كانا يقعان تحت السيطرة المشتركة‬ ‫لوزارتي الصحة والداخلية.‬
Do you know what that means?
‫هل تعرف معنى ذلك؟‬
No.
‫لا.‬
What went on there was controlled by the Ministry of the Interior.
‫ما حدث هناك كان تحت إشراف وزارة الداخلية.‬
Because that place was
‫لأن ذلك المكان‬
East Germany's experimental facility.
‫كان منشأة تجارب "ألمانيا الشرقية".‬